# Marie Smith

321 Main Street, Pflugerville, TX 12345 yourname@ennaildomain.com (678) 123-4567

### **PROFILE**

An Executive Housekeeper with eight years of experience delivering quality cleaning services and managing housekeeping teams for five-star hotels. A proven track record of identifying opportunities to enhance operational workflows and improve guest satisfaction scores.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Executive Housekeeper**

River Run Hotel, San Antonio, TX | January 2016 - Present

- Manage a team of 12 housekeepers to efficiently clean suites in a 250-room, five-star hotel, coordinate with the front desk to resolve guest issues, and contribute to a 98% guest satisfaction rating
- Implement new operational workflows and schedules to reduce completion time for cleaning assignments by eight minutes per room while maintaining five-star quality standards
- Identify opportunities to reduce cleaning waste and lead the implementation of green cleaning solutions to minimize safety risks and support the hotel's reputation as an environmentally conscious organization

# Housekeeper

Best Housekeepers, San Antonio, TX | January 2014-December 2015

- Achieved a promotion from housekeeper to head housekeeper in 100-room hotel within the first four months by providing impeccable service to guests and completing assignments ahead of schedule
- Cleaned 20 rooms per shift, sanitized bathrooms, living rooms, kitchenettes, and surfaces in guest suites, polished furnishings, and ensured compliance with hotel quality standards
- Improved bed-making practices, added artfully folded towels to enhance room presentation, which contributed to a 10% increase in guest satisfaction scores

## **EDUCATION**

# **Housekeeping Certificate Course**

International Housekeepers Association, December 2012-December 2013

High School Diploma, 3.8 GPA
One Town High School, San
Antonio TV August 2009, May

Antonio, TX, August 2008 - May 2012

## **KEY SKILLS**

- ♦ Housekeeping
- Commercial Cleaning
- Deep Cleaning
- Customer Service
- Furniture and Upholstery Cleaning

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

 Certified Executive Housekeeper